今年上半年的严重罪案
Serious crimes in the first half year...
九成是大圈做的
were done by the "Big Circle".
但是破案率就非常低
The ratio of conviction was low.
警务处长
The Commissioner is waiting for your plan.
他已经等了你那份破案计划书
三个月了
He has been waiting for 3 months.
你究竟想怎样？
what do you want to do?
我们要承认一个事实
we have to admit one thing.
其实破案要依赖线报
we need the informers!
大圈帮的特色就是团结，排外
The "Big Circle" group is cohesive.
不信任香港人
They don't trust Hong Kong people.
我们布落那些线起不到作用
The informers can't do much!
我现在的撒手锏就是以毒攻毒
I have got an idea, we have to use their own men...
以圈制圈
for undercover!
用回大陆人做卧底
Li Ho Tung, 34 years old.
Shandongese; son of senior cadre; rasied in Guangzhou.
Used to be platoon leader, company commander and battalion commander of PLA.
Quit in 1982.
And become the Captain of Guilin's public security bereau.
Qi King San, 31 years old.
Cantonese; son of senior cadre; graduated from Qinghua University.
Joined PLA at the age of 22.
Promoted to commander in 1979.
Seriously injured during Vietnamese war; having been awarded third-class merit.
Recovered in 1982 and become a police security inwuhan.
Guo Hok Kwan, 27 years old.
Cantonese; son of senior cadre.
went to Beijing and settled there with his father at the age of 12.
Graduated from Beijing Sports Academy.
Being a public security in Beijing starting form 1982.
In April, 1984, all three were arrested as they headed towards freedom.
They were sent to the reform-through-labour farm in Chini.
On July 14, 1986, they fled away from prison.
On July 16, 1986.
They stealthed into HK and were waiting to be sent back to Mainland.
你们走运了，我现在给两条路你们行
You are lucky, you have got two choices.
一是就押返大陆，一是就替我办事
1, to be sent back, 2, work for me!
请问你想我们干些什么事？
what do you want us to do?
卧底！
Undercover!
替我干两年
work for two years and be legalized!
干完之后就发身份证给你们
在香港长住，怎样？
Do you like to stay in HK?
我想我们都无得选择了！
Seems that we don't have a choice!
这些假发，一人一个
wigs, one each!
我会派一个做了十三年卧底的警察
An undercover police...
和你们拍档
...will help you!
他的名子叫做“大大” ！
His name is "Biggy"!
在香港投考皇家警察
To be a police in Hong Kong...
还难过考车牌
is more difficult than have a driving license.
万几个考生里面拣三、四十个出来
They only take 30 out of 10,000...
教育程度要大学毕业
and you need to be out of college.
英文又要说得好
Fluent English!
因为教我们的全都是外国人
Because the instructors speak English.
坦白说
well, you can't learn anything in Hong Kong.
你们落到来香港根本学不到什么东西
因为香港的环境太过复杂
Hong Kong is a mixed society.
就算你留十年、八年
Even if you spend 8-10 years here.
都是看到些表面
You only see the surface.
照我看呢…
I tell you...
最好带你们去庙街买些平价电器
Better get some cheap electrical appliance,
去金冠戏院看几场性变态的外语片
watch some sexual movies,
到返去那时就有排威了！
You'll have a proper pride when you back to China!
我带着你们三个家伙
Not sure if I am lucky with the three of you!
不知是走运还是我倒霉
你说呀！
Isn't it!
阿大大哥
Big Boss!
打住，不好哥前哥后，我受不起
wait! I can't bear it!
叫我大大行了！
Just call me Biggy!
阿大大，我们是希望立到功
Biggy, we are confident to be good.
可以在这里居留的！
we want to stay here!
see！ I see！
I see! I see!
怎样，我介绍这只U.S.A.的家乡鸡
well, you like this Kentucky Fried Chicken?
吃不吃得惯呀？
Call机，就是你们叫做的传呼机
This is the pager!
会震的，好像蟾蜍那样，有趣吗？
It vibrates like frog!
Call机又叫太空机
we call it space machine, too.
那些电波 “嘘” 一声射上去太空
The wave goes into space then reflects back!
反弹回来地球
给这部机接收了就 “嘟…”
And then "Do..."!
不可能的
Impossible, it's only a receiver!
这个是很简单的电波接收仪器
你懂吗？在这里乱说话！
You know nothing!
我以前当过无线电通讯兵
I was a radio operator!
如果你的传呼机坏了
I can fix your pager!
我懂得帮你修理好的
你朋友啊？
Your friends?
自助餐即是 “Buffet”
Self serve meals are "Buffet"!
“部飞” ？
Buffet?
“Buffet” 是自助餐的英语叫法
"Buffet" is the English spelling!
我老爸第一次带我来食Buffet的时候
The first time I went for a buffet.
我饿足三日三夜
I didn't eat for 3 days!
清了肠胃才来吃餐饱的
And my stomach was all empty.
拿几多都可以吗？
Get as much as you like?
当然！
Yes! Take it easy, don't be rude!
不要急不及待，失礼人了！
如果吃完这餐
After I've finished this meal,
坐到肚饿，又吃夜晚那餐行不行呢？
can I wait and have dinner as well?
再吃宵夜都行
You can even have supper!
还有啊，如果你顶得着困
And have breakfast...
明早还可以吃早餐呢！
in the morning!
你前世未吃过饭吗？
You didn't eat in your last life?
无米落肚，我还是觉得不饱的
I feel hungry without rice!
那边有只龙虾，手快有，手慢无
A lobster over there! Only one left, take it!
你要呀大大哥！
You take it, Big Boss!
我不能吃虾的，你吃呀！
I can't have prawns, you have it!
唔该（谢谢）！
Thanks!
先生，欣赏完未呢？
Have you finished looking at it?
只龙虾要来陈设的！
The lobster is for decoration!
陈设又放在这里，坑人吗！
what for putting it there? wanna scare me?
外面那个猪头炳叫 “长洲”
The hill out there is Cheung Chow.
做贼赃买卖，专干大案的
The place for stolen goods.
随随便便一年有千多万到他手的！
The turnover is around $50M!
你识他吗？
Do you know him?
不识，礼貌上打个招呼吧了！
No, but we say hello!
懂得接着上呀！
You are smart!
他手上有这么多资料
He has got a lot of information.
找个机会，等我们和他沟通一下！
Try to talk to him!
你决定吧大哥！
You give the order, boss!
不好说笑了，大大！
Stop kidding, Biggy!
我们是好朋友来的嘛！
we are good friends!
打住，不要老友前老友后呀！
Don't mention friendship!
我只是你们临时指导员来的
I am only your temp commander.
那么指导员，我有一个提议
I have a suggestion, commander
我想申请每人一支枪
Everyone should have a pistol.
香港做卧底好惨的，无枪的！
Undercovers don't have guns!
但是我们的工作好危险的！
It's dangerous to work in H.K.!
你镇定些，我有路买的嘛！
Don't worry, I know how to get the guns!
不过你们记着，你们现在是大圈
You are criminals, don't try to get the guns.
你们不应该申请
Don't try to get the guns.
应该用非法的手段来弄到手的
Hire from the guns smugglers!
两支航空曲，每支蚊半
Two.45 government, fifty thousand dollars each.
一支麦林点四四，两蚊
One.44 Magnum, twenty thousand dollars!
每支赠送十发子弹
10 bullets each.
价钱高了些！
It's too expensive!
大哥，你们拿着这三支生财工具
Hay, you have these three pistols!
一单买卖就赚几十蚊啦！
You can make a few hundred dollars in a second!
点会高啊？
It wouldn't be too expensive?
跛张的价钱公道的
He is reliable!
不会骗你的老板
满意就付款吧！
Pay if you want it!
学军，给他！
Hok Kwan, pay!
你那份照规矩哦！
Your usual rule!
慢慢计啦！
Say it again!
是了，那三十发子弹呢？
Right, the 30 rounds of bullets?
我入去拿给你吧！
I get them for you!
黑鬼唐？
Negro Tong?
黑鬼唐！
Negro Tong!
大大，我等今天等了三年了
Biggy, I have waited for 3 years!
别动呀！
Don't move!
干什么呀，嬲我无拜你山吗？
what, upset I didn't visit you in jail?
废话，上次找你出货
Rubbish, last time you helped me.
一转身就给警察拉了
I ended up in jail!
契弟，出卖我？
Bastard, betrayed me!
我契弟，我出卖你？
Me, bastard? I betrayed you?
我也给警察拉了！
The police got me too!
肋骨都打断几条
I broke my ribs as well!
我大大出来混是说义气的
I wanna sincere!
如果我和那些警察合作
You would spend 3 more years. If I told the cops!
你最少坐多三、四年呀！
你现在这样说法，即是硬生生冤枉我啦！
what do you mean, wanna frame me!
你说到会飞都无用
It's no use how you say it!
我今日就要杀你
I wanna kill you today.
看看这三个人什么来头
Look at these three pistols.
去…去那边…行！
Go...over there!
别动呀！
Don't move!
唐哥！
Tong!
赤泥？
Chick Lai?
两个月前逃出来的
I came here two months ago.
赤泥在那里？
which prison camp?
建联！
Kin Luen!
谁是监头？
who was in-charge?
山东佬，邦爷！
Uncle Pong, the man from San Tung!
正宗屎忽鬼来的
He really is a pimp!
还未死吗？那个臭家伙！
He is still alive. That bastard!
唐哥，七年前是赤泥
Tong, in Chick Lai 7 years ago.
领导五一大暴动那个黑鬼唐就是你？
You were the head of the 5-1 riot!
我们在里面
The old ones always talk about you!
时常都听到一些前辈提起你的
你们听过我个名？
You have heard about my name?
是呀，唐哥你好出名的！
Yes, you were famous!
这个反骨仔是你的老朋友吗？
He is your friend?
是呀，我们是老友来的
Yes, we are old friends!
打住，不要老友前老友后
Shut up! who the hell is your old friend.
你呀！不过是我们的
Don't forget you are our temp commander!
临时买枪指导员吧了
你这个打靶，原来你是做反骨仔的
You are an informer, you bastard!
那些钱给回他们！
Give me back the money!
不是嘛唐哥，那我有什么好处啊？
You said we have it all!
拿来！
Give it to me!
大家大圈的，无谓为了些桂枝仔伤感情
Don't spoil our friendship because of the bastard.
这家伙的事，你给句说话我好了！
You tell me one thing!
我们什么都看不到啊
we didn't see anything.
我们今日入来赤柱是游水的
we are here to swim!
这一枪取你命
I want your life.
对不起，我不记得拿回条游水裤
I am sorry, I forgot my trunks!
什么游水裤呀？
what trunks?
不要啊，大佬！
Don't, please! Let me go, take the pistol!
这些枪你拿去，拿去啦！
我什么都看不到
I have seen nothing.
我…我出去游水！
I...I go to swim!
No...
Betrayed me?
出卖我？
怎样？
Thanks.
谢谢！
Come over, my left ear can't hear!
今次发瘟了
我只耳朵好像给支枪震聋了
不是吧！你掩着右耳
It shouldn't, cover your right ear.
学军，你去他左面大声说话
Hok Kwan, speak loudly on his left.
看他听不听到
- See if he can hear! - Yes.
死啦，真是听不到啊！
I can't hear a thing!
你行近些，对正些，大声些试下
Come closer, try to speak loudly!
死仔，玩我！
You bastard, fool me! I have enough!
还玩我不够啊！
I heard you told Negro Tong the other day...
前日你和黑鬼唐说
打住，不要老友前老友后
"Shut up, I am not your friend!"
我个脑即时 “轰” 一声
I thought I would finish!
我想死定啦！
以为你们真是不理我了！
I thought you leave me alone!
别傻了，男子汉大丈夫嘛！
You fool, don't be narrow minded!
没这么小气的，大家是战友嘛！
we are comrades!
东哥！
Tung!
我碰到一个以前部队中的
I met my good friend in the army and his sister.
好朋友和他妹妹
有靓女呀？
Beautiful girl?
惩越战那时，他救过我的
He saved my life in the war.
他请我去他家里吃饭，我想请你批准
He invited me for dinner, I hope I can go!
他是怎样下来的？
when did he come?
五年前申请下来的
He got the permission five years ago.
小心点，别暴露身份
Be careful, don't expose yourself.
程警司！
Inspector Ching!
资本主义社会下产生的经济犯罪手法
The crimes under the property of HK...
真是光怪陆离
is really amazing!
我们现在接触到一宗
we have a "Self-kidnapping" case!
自己劫自己的怪案
案中珠宝商勾结坏份子
A jewelry shop owner rubbed his own shop.
打劫自己的店铺，以骗取保险金
And tried to get the compensation!
而事后坏份子吞没赃物
His partners got away with the jewelry.
还勒索珠宝商
And blackmailed the owner.
透过大大的关系
Through Biggy...
珠宝商打算聘请我们代为出头
The owner asked us to get the jewelleries back.
夺回珠宝
订金在这里，你数数它呀大哥！
Boss, this is the deposit!
学军，数数它
Hok Kwan, check it.
不好意思几位老板
Sorry, we're late!
今日小姐们迟了点上班！
到来很久了吗？
Let me kiss you!
和你调个位
Let's change.
不用了！
No...!
对不起，不好意思！
Excuse me!
你的男朋友啊？
Your boyfriend?
傻仔，他是我契哥来的
He is my cousin!
不过他喜欢跳舞，所以时常上来！
He always comes here cause he likes dancing!
我以为他拥有你
I thought you were his.
你说什么啊？
what did you say?
对不起，我说错话
I am sorry!
我知道你想着些什么事的
I know what you are thinking.
不过你不要乱听人家说话
Don't listen to what people say!
我们这里不是个个小姐
Not every girl goes out with the guests here.
肯陪人客出街的
树大一定是有枯枝的啦
There are bad ones in a good family too!
一定有些人不自爱的
香港地行行都是这样的！
Every job is the same here in H.K.!
很多女明星一样为了钱出来卖身
Some of the stars "work" for money!
不过都是看自己的
It all depends!
我就不是这么贱格的！
I do behave!
我嫌钱腥的，我情愿穷些，辛苦些
I don't really like money!
你说我这个人是否很硬颈呢？
Am I too mean?
怎会呢，我看你的人格值得敬佩就真
No, I respect you!
多谢你！
Thanks!
我想找兴仔
I want to see Siu Hing.
什么，兴仔是你叫的吗？
what?
兴哥！
- Dear Hing! - Is that you?
你就是？
I am camel, Siu Hing is my superior!
我就是驼龙，兴哥是我的大佬
大佬，那个表叔来了
Hing, that bastard is coming.
我叫李向东，我是大圈的
I am Li Ho Tung, from China.
我是代表杨老板和你说话的！
I represent Boss Yeung!
你和我说话啊？
who are you talking to?
他和我说话啊？
who is he talking too?
凭什么呀？
what has he got in hand?
姓杨那家伙派这呆子来
That Yeung bastard, sent a fool over.
算什么？
what does it mean?
这样更侮辱过打你两巴呢，大佬！
This means he doesn't respect you!
我要求你在两日之内
I want you to hand over your stuff,
即刻将所有的货无条件交还给我们
to us in two days' time!
这个是我传呼机号码
That's my paging number!
你想清楚，两日之内随时传呼我吧！
Think it over, contact me in these two days!
等我扑醒你啦，知不知和谁说话？
Do you know who you are talking to?
我祥兴在油尖区
My status in T.S.T. is the same as a mayor!
就等如是你们广东省的省长
无论谁见到我都要立正，敬礼
Everyone has to salute at me!
只有我说给你听怎做
Only I can give the order.
你无资格教我怎样做的
You can't tell me what to do.
明不明白啊？
- Do you understand? - I understand!
我明白！
明日是我阿妈生日，打人不吉利
It's my mum's birthday tomorrow, we'll wait.
算你走运啦！
You are lucky!
回去说给姓杨知道，叫他不用再说了
Tell Mr. Yeung not to negotiate anymore.
我和我老母做完大寿
I have to celebrate my mum's birthday.
就会替他老母做忌，明不明白呀？
Then I will put his mum to sleep, understand?
我明白！
I understand!
还有，大笨圈！
Stupid!
我以后不想在油尖区里见到你
I don't wanna see you in T.S.T. anymore. Understand?
明不明白呀？
Understand!
我明白！
看什么呀，大笨圈！
what are you looking at?
下次见到你，剪掉你老二啦！
If I see you again, I chop yours off!
走！
Let's go!
今晚的行动
The target tonight is to insult Siu Hing publicly!
就是要在大庭广众里惩罚兴仔
成功的话
If we succeed.
我们就会争取到
we can build up our fame instantly!
在最短时间内建立声名
打入香港的黑社会犯罪阶层
And joint the Hong Kong underground.
对方人多，战略上占绝大的优势
They have more people, so they are better off.
不过亦有极大的弱点
But they have their weak point too.
就是他们根本无任何作战的心理准备
They are not ready to fight!
而且兴仔为人卑鄙
And because Siu Hing is selfish.
出席的各路英雄亦未必会插手
People may not help him!
这个亦都是香港人不团结的劣根性
That's Hong Kong people,
我们需要作出迅速
and we have to attack fast!
和决定性的要点攻击
然后尽快撤退
and retreat quickly!
整个过程不可以超过五分钟，明白吗？
The whole operation is no more than 5 minutes!
明白！
I understand!
利害，军事行动，十足打仗一样
Great, a military operation!
人家在上面不用召人
we don't need outside support!
分分钟都有几百个人在那里
一人一笃口水都浸死我们！
we get drawn easily!
要点攻击，我们得四个人而已
Main point attack!
上去开台打麻雀差不多
Four of us only better play Mahjong.
这些叫做 “找死” 啊！
we will surely die!
你的任务是负责两电
Your job is "Two Electrics".
还指挥我做事呢！
Give me orders!
不是呢，我是诚意邀请你参予
No, I sincerely ask you to join in.
我没说不做，我像无义气的人吗？
I didn't say no!
不过我想请教一下，战友
But tell me.
什么事叫做两电哪？
what "Two Electrics" is?
就是破坏电话总机
That's the phone and the switch!
和负责总电灯的开关掣
为什么我要做这些无聊的事呀？
why ask me to do such silly things?
因为这两个岗位
Because it's safe for you!
对你的性命来说是最安全
你们先混进去
- You two sneak in first! - Yes!
是！
贵哥，这么早到呀，随便…！
Boss Kwan, good on you!
恭喜！
Congratulations!
成哥，谭Sir，招呼不到，随便…！
Boss Shing, Tang Sir, thank you for you coming!
你死了去那里呀？
You get lost!
叫了你们七点前好到的了嘛！
I said before seven, now it's eight already!
现在几点钟呀？
what time is it?
以为你们撞车全死了！
I thought you got run over!
阿妈临出门口，条腰好痛
Mum's back hurt when coming!
要吃ABC才行得动嘛！
She had to take the drugs!
你在吃ABC
The guests were having prawn noodles!
那些人客就猛点虾球伊面
今日我分分钟白做呀！
I earn nothing today!
我都说了不好做的啦
I said no celebrations before!
生日一早过了啦！
你个仆街，这么大声是否想落个仔面啊
why talk to me that loud!
看看你件死人衫，穿得像拜山似的
The clothes are for corpse only!
正菁也！
That brings bad luck!
别这样，阿哥！
Stop that!
什么呀？驳嘴！
Damn it, respect me will you!
全都去死！
Go to hell!
No.1 ！
No.1!
各位嘉宾
Everybody, it's Mrs. Ko's birthday today.
今日是高老太的荣寿好日子
我代表本酒楼送首生日歌给高老太
Let's celebrate by singing!
兴哥，电话，是钟表行姓杨的打来
Go to hell!
Hing, your call, it's from Mr. Yeung!
祝你生日快乐…！
Happy birthday to you...!
全部趴低
Get down on your knees!
控制两电部门的手足给个讯息出来
Give me the signal!
打鼓！
Hit the drum!
上，上啊！
Come, let's go!
无义气！
You chicken!
好了
The whole place is under our control!
大家明白了我们已经控制了这个场面
兄弟
well you don't have to use the pistols!
是英雄好汉就不用拿支枪出来靠吓
有本事就收起支枪，大家一起从长计议
Put down your gun, let's talk!
全部趴低，趴低！
Get down on your knees!
各位
Everybody we've to solve our problem!
我现在和兴仔解决一些私人的恩怨
请各单位的前辈给面子我李向东
And hope that I get the respect.
不要插手落这件事，明不明白？
Please stay out of it?
明白…！
- Understand? - Understand...
说自己的罪状
Tell us your sin!
是我不对，吞了人家的货
I was wrong to take people's goods.
我愿意退还出来
I promise to hand them back!
大声读！
Read it loud!
我兴仔，是契弟
Me, Siu Hing is a pimp.
今日其实不是我老母生日
It's not my mum's birthday, I wanna rip off!
存心捡兄弟便宜
我不孝，我闹老母，我打细妹
I am bad to my family!
我不是人，我是只狗
I am a beast!
大声些！
Louder!
我今日真是罪有应得
I deserve what I should!
以后复仇，我活该给人打死
If not, you chop me!
撤退！
Retreat!
打鼓！
Hit the drum!
Let's go!
走了，无事啦！
理不过，走了！
Please stay out, let's go!
你无事呀嘛？
- Are you alright? - You betrayer!
无义气！
饮杯水了，妈！
Mum, a cup of tea!
我今晚真是饮得杯落
Let's drink!
我条气顺了
I'm very happy!
普天下被压迫的人民都有一本血泪账
All working people had a debt written in blood and tears.
要报仇！要伸冤！要报仇！要伸冤！
They want to take revenge!
血债要用血来偿
They wanna avenge!
消灭坐山雕，人民得解放
Finish the power, release the people.
翻身做主人，深山见太阳
To be the master, and see the sun again!
好啊！
Good!
京生，欠一个人打麻雀，入来！
we need one more person to play Mahjong!
你和我个妹几合拍
You match with my sister.
介绍个老友给你们两个识
Come, meet my good friend!
我在解放军的死党，一齐出生入死
we were like brothers in war!
京生！
King San!
杨才，花名豺狼！      杨大哥！
- Nick name "wolf"! - Boss Yeung!
叫阿狼得了！
Just call me "wolf"!
李明豹！
- Li Ming Pal! - How are you?
好吗？
- Boss Pal! - Come, sit down!
豹哥！              来，坐！
兄弟，你们最近敦煌酒楼那件事好利害啊
we done well at Tung wong!
你怎知？
How did you know?
落了来几年就身光颈靓
we got rich in few years time.
你估我们做什么？
Guess what we do?
朋友的朋友刚说起
Friend's friend told me that.
开档啦！
Let's play Mahjong!
原来星期日
You suspect their l.D. since Sunday?
你已经开始怀疑他们的身份了？
为什么你三日之后先报告？
why tell me after 3 days?
你不要忘记我们都是公安人员出身
Don't forget that we are cops!
不应该同情那些犯罪份子
No sympathy on criminals!
阿虎和我都是一六九师出身
Ah Fu and I were in 169 squad.
我们曾经出生入死
we stayed together.
但是他现在可能是罪犯
He may be a criminal now.
对破坏社会秩序的坏份子
He is upsetting the society.
我们绝对不可以手软
Don't be too passionate!
七九年打越南
when we were fighting with the Vietkung in 79.
我给迫击炮碎片打中
I was hit by a bomb!
阿虎虽然亦都中了枪
And Ah Fu was shot too.
但是他仍然背着我走四里路
But he carried me for four miles!
送我去战地医院
And he had saved my life!
那样我才捡回性命
My job is to charge him today!
今日我为了职责，检举他出来
已经觉得好内疚
I feel guilty.
我这几晚都睡不安宁，你知不知呀？
I didn't get to sleep lately?
大陆人在这里给人歧视，为了什么？
People look down on the men from China,
就因为有阿虎这样的人
all because of people like Ah Fu.
这么辛苦，这么艰难落到来
They commit crimes here!
不好好地做人，反而走去打、砸、抢
They become thieves here!
这些倒乱份子是应该消灭的
They should be kept in jail!
什么事呀，黑口黑面，死老豆吗？
Shut up, father is dead?
闭上你的衰口！
Shut up your dirty mouth!
狗嘴长不出象牙来
You can never be a gentleman.
对不起，我老爸入了医院病了几个月
I am sorry, my dad is in the hospital!
希望他吉人天相，大步槛过啦，来！
I hope that he will recover!
东哥做的水饺真是No.1 ！
Boss, your shrimp dumplings are good!
这些水饺是你老豆教你做的？
Did your dad teach you?
是呀，我爸爸是山东人哪！
Yes, my dad is from Shan Tung!
在这个时候吃碗水饺来哀掉你老豆
To have shrimp dumplings now is meaningful!
真是够意思！
we can pay our respect to your dad!
京生，你不是喜欢我做的水饺吗？
King San, you said you like my dumplings.
我做了整天了
I had spent a whole day, do have some!
你不是不赏面吧！
来，凉了！
Come, it's cold!
长洲今次求你们帮他，要打蛇随棍上
It's a chance Cheung Chow asks for our help!
他和这么多人出货
He has been a sales representative!
无论如何都迫他说出来
Try to press him to tell us!
这样就可以追查到很多事情来啦！
Then we will have a lot of cases!
-这么人齐呀，你估选美吗？ -认真赏面，请坐！
Please come in!
长洲！
Cheung Chow!
赏面，多谢！
Thanks for coming!
赏面…！
说好是三十五元替他们出货的！
The deal was $350,000!
那几兄弟忽然间说我不老实
The Kwong brothers said I lied!
说起码值多十元
Obviously they put pressure on us?
大佬啊，那即是明抢我的
说不说口齿先
They don't keep their words!
所以我一直都好憎那些大圈的
That's why I hate "Big Circles"!
不是…只是那班大圈
No, I mean the people!
影响到你们的，你说是不是呀？
That spoils your image!
去胡混，有人静静地去胡混
Some one is fooling around.
姓江的这四兄弟
The Kwong brothers are very mysterious.
平时很少和其他大圈交往
They seldom fix up with other men from China.
唯一知道他们出入的场所
The usual place they go is the Mahjong house.
就是瑞兴麻雀馆
They play for high stakes, minimum is $500.
打好大的，打的都五百、一千
这班人的钱怎来，无人知
The source of money is unknown.
他们都是第一次找长洲出货
It's the 1st time they wanna trade with Cheung Chow.
你盘算他们会带几多人来呢？
How many people will go together?
他们四兄弟加起来，已经是一支军队
The four of them make up an army!
不会放长洲在眼内
The Kwongs won't be afraid of Cheung Chow.
不过这样，他们又不知长洲找什么人出头
Don't know who will stand for Cheung Chow!
所以今次他们好可能带枪
So they will have their guns.
兄弟，和气生财啊！
Pal, keep calm!
做什么呀？
what? I am not an executor!
你以为我现在去执行打靶任务啊！
我惊你满脑子什么思想
I am afraid your mind is filled with killings,
打击坏份子，不要手软那些坏事呀！
and no passion!
买了午夜场戏票了！
I have the mid-night show tickets!
你要记着
Remember to pick us up in this area!
保持在这条街的范围内接应我们
成了，你说了几十次啦！
I know, you have said a hundred times!
我买了午夜场戏票了！
I have got the mid-night show tickets!
是了，你说姓江的有四兄弟是不是？
Right, the four Kwongs are really brothers?
是！
Yes!
干什么呀？
why?
怎样？
How is it?
我调派广西那年
I had grabbed a rubber called Kwong in Kong Sai!
捉过一个姓江的抢劫犯
但是他好像得两兄弟而已
But he should have two brothers.
没这么巧吧？
was it that co-incidental?
没收到消息说他们落了来香港
The data have no trace that they are in H.K.
应该不是他们
I don't think so!
东哥！生哥！军哥！来…！
Heung Tung! King San! Hok Kwan! Come on...!
请入来！
- Come in! - Please!
请内进！
几位，请入去！
Please come in!
长哥，还有人会到！
No body here!
开壶什么茶先呢？
what would you like to drink?
普洱、寿眉、水仙一样一些啦！
Po Lee, Sau Mei, Jasmine, all of them!
好啊！
Right!
请内进！
This way please!
糟，真是他们！
- Damn, it really is he! - what shall we do?
怎办？
Be alert, get ready at any time!
提高警觉，随时会战斗
记着，我们的身份不可以泄露
Remember, never expose our identity!
几位，请入来！
Come in, please!
几位大哥，刚刚打电话传呼你们
The bosses have gone to call you!
来…过来坐…这边…！
Come...please!
等我介绍，海哥，河哥，民哥，川哥
This is Boss Hoi, Boss Hok, Boss Ming, Boss Chu!
这几个好兄弟，东哥，生哥，军哥
Tung! San! King!
大家自己人
we are of the same origin.
正所谓同声同气，怎样都好说些嘛！
we can feel free! Alright?
你说是不是？
- Hoi, what would you like? - Lung Chan!
饮什么茶啊，海哥？
龙井！
Lung Chan, get me a bottle of Lung Chan!
龙井？飞壶龙井过来！
好啊！
Yes!
这几位兄弟新落来的吗？
They just came out?
我们从赤泥逃出来
They are from Check Lai.
无路走，所以被逼要落来
They had no alternative, so they left.
敦煌酒楼打兴仔那件事
The fight at Tung wong restaurant was done by them!
就是他们的杰作
Tung, you look familiar!
东哥，好面善！
我们在那里见过面？
where did we meet before?
见过我实记得的！
I can remember even just seeing once!
你以前有无在桂林住过？
Have you ever stayed in Kwong Sai Kwai Lam?
未有机会，我一直都是住在广州
No chance, I stayed in Canton all the time!
你真的一直没有离开过广州？
How come you stayed there all the time?
你说什么话？
what did you say?
别装傻，桂林话你懂得听的
You should know the language of Kwong Sai!
老兄
Pals, are you talking business or kidding?
你们是来谈判的，还是来开玩笑的？
可以说清楚吗？
Can you tell me?
你曾经在桂林公安局做过事，是不是？
You had worked at the Kwai Lam Security Dept?
是你，错不了！
It's you, can't escape!
我记得你的手掌有枪伤
You have gun wound on your arm, what does it mean?
你不用装神弄鬼了
大哥啊，叫了你们和气生财的了！
I told you that politeness can make money already!
他叫我传呼你的
- He asks me to look for you! - How is he?
他怎样？
He won't get through!
没得救了！
阿江…我是阿狼
Ah Kong...I am Leung!
有什么事说给我听？
what do you want to tell me?
究竟是那班人干的？
who did this? I will finish them for you!
我一定帮你干掉他们！
Kwong Sai Security office, "Big Circle" undercover!
广西公安局，大圈卧底！
阿江…！
Ah Kong!
收拾好那些行医仪器
Hide the instrument!
打电话报警，说他自己摸上来
Call the police, say he came here himself.
我从来没有在这里出现过，你知的啦！
I have not been here, understand?
无问题！
Understand!
Fuck！ Fuck！
FUCK! FUCK!
“勿” 是什么意思？
what's that meaning?
头条啊，黑帮无法无天
The headline-4 got killed in the public!
闹市枪杀四人
Trouble this time!
这黑镬子走不了啦！
Sir, they discovered that Heung Tung is a cop.
程Sir，对方认出阿东是差人
他们身份如果泄露了出去
If their identity got revealed.
不可以再执行任务
They can't carry out their duty anymore.
要执包袱返乡下了！
They have to go back to China!
闭上你的嘴，不关你事！
Shut up, none of your business here!
敦煌酒楼一次，现在又一次
First in Tung wong Rest. It's the second time.
认出你又怎样！
So what if they recognize you?
在大陆做差人，落到来不可以做贼吗？
A cop back there, a thief here is the same.
香港很多差人转行做贼啦！
Many cops turn to be thieves here!
完全是你做贼心虚，作出过度反应
You are too nervous!
绝对不可能！
It's impossible!
在大陆从来无差人转行做贼
China cops will never be thieves.
他们都是有枪
They have pistols!
不通我们不可以自保吗？
Can't we self-defend ourselves?
我们是差人
we're a policeman!
打击坏份子，绝对不能手软的
It's our job to fight crime, we have to be tough!
这里是香港，香港是有法律的
Here is Hong Kong, it's a place of law and order.
不是在街见到那些贼就打死他
we can't just kill the thieves.
你是什么差人啊，是偷渡劳改犯而已
You are only a sneaker!
我劳改偷渡，完全是政治思想问题
I sneak in only for freedom.
你不好侮辱我人格
Please do respect me!
你再顶我的嘴，就捉你入去坐两年监
Shut up, or I put you in jail!
然后再押你返大陆
And send you back to Mainland China. Fuck.
Fuck！
你们这些朋友好可能就是
Yours friends could be the ones we look for!
我们找了很久的悍匪来的
They killed 2 guards and a pedestrian!
他们打死过两个护卫员
打伤过一个路人
Hurting four policemen, keep an eye on them!
四个警察，盯紧他们啊！
我是要生口，不要随意又打死他们
Catch them alive!
程Sir，长洲他怎样？
Sir, how is Cheung Chow!
我收藏他在特别隔离房
I hide him in an isolated room.
他晚晚都发恶梦
He has nightmares everyday!
惊你这班狂人会杀死他
走！
Let's go!
饮 “B” 酒！
Let's go to have some bear!
啤酒，不是B酒！
Beer! Not bear! FUCK!
Fuck！
阿虎今日不回来吗？
will Ah Fu come back?
几日都不见人，都不知干什么
He is missing for a few days.
好热啊！
So hot!
那个冷气坏坏的，你喝不喝啤酒？
The air-cond. is no good, you want some beer?
我自己拿行了！
I get it myself!
好热啊！
So hot!
怕什么丑呢，成年人了
Don't be shy, you are old enough!
穿回衣服，有些正经事和你谈
Put on your clothes, I got to talk to you!
大家都是自己人，本来什么都可以谈
Actually we can talk about anything!
以前没这个必要
It wasn't time to let Ah Fu tell you!
我叫阿虎先不好跟你说
其实你都想到，我们三个是做明攻
I think you can guess!
我想了有几个月 ，去做间银行
we plan to rob the bank!
有成六、七百粒现水
There will be around $7.0M.
我想找你和你两个兄弟帮手
I hope you two can help me!
饮啤酒啦！
Some beer!
为何会找我们？
why look for us suddenly?
一来，你们的身手够好，和我们差不多
well, you are cruel enough!
二来，你和阿虎的交情，信得过
And because of Ah Fu, we can trust you!
三来，和我们一向合作的那几个
Our old partners are gone!
突然间潜逃了
And they can't have the share!
注定我们有缘啦！
God， come again！
God, come again!
Madam， help
Madam, help, madam...Come again!
Madam… Come again！
It's okay， Mariana！
It's O.K., Mariana!
Him， my darling， okay！
Him, my darling, O.K.!
Okay， I see！
OK, I see!
是谁人干的？
That team of people?
谁干谁干，天晓得！
who knows who did it?
又无凿个字在额头，又无穿着制服的
There was no uniform, no writing!
大圈仔！
The "Big Circle"!
最衰你个死人Mariana！
Because of your Mariana!
干什么不问清楚就开门给人入来
You let people in so easily!
刚才我洗完头回来
I was drying my hair when they rushed in.
那些人就扑过来了
有无污辱你呀？
Did they insult you?
当然是无啦！
No!
打我啊，问我长洲躲藏在那里
But hit me, ask me where Cheung Chow was hiding.
你看看
Look at my fingers!
十只手指都给他们打到扁了！
阴功！
Oh no!
我不依呀，打烂了所有东西
I don't care, they have taken anything!
还拿了我的首饰
You stupid！
YOU STUPlD!
我刚才想了想傻到想自杀呀！
I was going to kill myself!
不要这样，达令，不要哭啦！
Stop that darling, don't cry!
你不见了多少钱哪？
How much did you lose?
加上姐妹放在我这里的手饰
Altogether is more than $200,000!
大约二十几万
这么多钱啊？
That much?
你去那里？
where are you going?
去那里不好
Anywhere, just to leave this place!
总之离开这个伤心地啦！
这些姐妹那样信我
How can I face them, they trust me!
我怎样向人家交待
钱等我想想办法
Let me think!
你不用走，我可以保护你呀！
I can protect you, don't go!
你可以保护我一世吗？
Can you protect me for my whole life?
那些人说，如果我知道些事不说
Those people warned me of telling the truth.
就会毁我容的！
Or they will hurt me on my face!
我知道长洲那件事你有份的
I know you were involved in Cheung Chow's case.
我宁愿死，刚才都无出卖你
I won't betray you!
谁叫我喜欢你呢，前世欠了你的！
Because I can't help loving you!
算吧，学军！
Forget it, Hok Kwan!
我们分开吧，有缘无份！
we better break up!
达令…不要离开我
Darling, don't leave me alone.
无了你，我会死的！
I will die without you!
我以后见不到你，你估我心不痛吗？
My heart breaks without seeing you!
不过长痛不如短痛呀！
But shorten the pain!
我跟着你都无好日子过的
It won't be good if we stay together.
你出来混的，今日不知明日事
You don't have a steady income!
我怎可以为我的爱人日日提心吊胆呀
And I worry about your life!
我整天在幻想
It's only my fancy!
如果我有三、四十万
I will go with you if I had $350,000!
我就会带你一齐走
we go to Hawaii!
一齐去夏威夷，在世外桃源里
我们重新开始
And start all over again!
过些自由自在的生活
三、四十万不是一个问题
$350,000 is not a problem!
但是我不可以走的！
But I can't leave!
你无护照啊？
Don't you have a passport?
不要紧
I can get you a forge passport!
我识人可以帮你买个假护照
这样全世界都可以去啦！
Then we can go anywhere!
有证都是无用的！
It's no use having the passport!
为什么？
why?
我不能说给你听的
I can't tell you!
原来你说来说去都是想玩我的
So you lie to me!
你由头到尾都是无诚意的
You only play with me!
你走，走呀
I can swear...!
达令…我可以发毒誓
I really want to marry you!
我是一心一意娶你做老婆的！
你正衰人来的
Go to hell, I won't trust you!
我以后都不会信男人的了！
好了…我说给你知
O.K. I tell you!
但你要守秘密！
But you have to keep to secret!
我不是什么事坏份子，我是差人
I am an informer!
我在大陆当差的
The police wants us to be undercovers!
所以香港警方逼我们做卧底
什么？
what?
干什么，有心事啊？
what's wrong?
没有！
Nothing!
大家战友嘛，说出来听听
我刚刚收到个消息
我老爸的病好危险
估不到你这么高大都这么孝顺！
I didn't know that you love your parents!
我阿妈很早就死了
My mum died early!
我两父子相依为命
I live with my dad!
我做军人或者做差人他都引以为荣
He is proud of me as a cop!
说真呢，我老爸是个老实的教员
He is a good teacher!
我这次从劳改场那里偷渡下来香港
This time I sneaked into Hong Kong!
连累他给人审到心脏病发
He was questioned real hard.
你说，如果他为我死了
So, if my dad died because of me.
你叫我怎做人呢？
what do I do?
天要下雨
It looks like raining!
没有办法呀！
Nothing I can do!
都是说回些正经事先
Let's talk business!
究竟是那班人同江氏兄弟出头呢？
who is behind the four brothers?
查不到！
Don't know?
不过外面周围有消息流出
It was said that I was responsible!
说这件事是我促成的
我要全背上身的了！
It gets on me!
不过到目前为止
But nobody will know you did it!
都未有人知道是你们干的
我明天就去新界，去我老表那里躲藏先
I will hide away in the New Territories!
去多久？
For how long?
很难说的
Hard to say!
无那么风大雨大了，就回来！
I wait till things calm down!
惯啦，年中实有几次要潜逃的
I am used to this way of living!
对不起！
Sorry!
我现在才体会到做卧底的滋味
I now realize your way of life!
我命硬，死不去！
I am tough, I survive!
我不似得你们打过仗
I haven't been to wars.
不过你看看
But look at me!
全身上下，由头到脚，无块肉是好的
I have stitches allover my body!
有些是古惑仔弄的，有些是差佬弄的
Some by thieves, some by police.
我做了这行十三年
To do my job it's been 1 3 years.
人不似人，鬼不似鬼
Don't know what I look like!
做卧底正一开大又死，开细又死！
An informer will die sooner or later!
遇到差佬就惊他当你是贼
The cops think that I am a thief.
遇到古惑仔又惊他知你是差佬
The thief may think that I am a cop!
日日提心吊胆，晚晚都无觉好睡
I worry all the time!
你大哥干完这两年后
You can stay on for two years and change.
可以转行做第二样事
我，我是什么？
As for me?
朋友又无，老婆又走路
I have no friends and my wife is gone!
说得难听一点，将来就算我死在街里
To be pessimistic!
都无英国旗盖啦！
I won't have the national salute!
你说像什么！
what do you think?
你说啊！
You say it!
他老母！
Damn it!
你明的啦！
Do you understand?
我明，我明白的！
Yes, I understand!
你知不知呀！
Do you know!
你们几个初初来时，傻得几可爱
But you were quite smart!
我知你们看不起我的！
I know you look down on me!
实说我做事断估，怕死，不修边幅
You said that I was a worthless coward.
是不是？你不用不认了！
Right? Don't deny that!
最初我是觉得你很嚣张的！
I felt that you were bad!
现在呢？
And now?
还是很嚣张，不过蛮算几有义气
But you are a real pal!
我够知了，不用你说呀，挑！
I know, you don't have to say!
我想做完今年就退休不干了
I will retire after this year.
我储了几年钱的
I have saved more than $100,000!
多就无了，十万，八万啦！
想搞些小生意，打工无发达的！
I can run my own business!
这个送给你
This is for you!
送给我？
For me?
真的？
Really?
说开又说，你包的饺子No.1 ，真是棒
Your dumplings are good!
我将来回来的时候，记得包给我吃啊！
Give me some more other time!
你吃得几多只啊？
How many can you have? 50?
五十只啊？
80!
八十只呀！
再见！
杀了我…！
Kill me...!
杀了我，无东西说呀！
Kill me, I don't know anything!
老友，你这里是不是有病啊？
Bastard, something wrong here?
你说，是那边班人干的
I give you a chance, tell me who did it!
我会给条路你行
I'll fulfill your wish to be a hero!
你不肯说，硬要做英雄，我会成全你
我…我什么都不知
I...I don't know!
等我打他两下心口
Let me punch him and let the rats...
他张开口一叫的时候
这些老鼠走了入去他的肚里乱跑
get into his mouth.
我就不信他不说
Then he will talk!
好啦，你的记忆恢复来啦！
O.K. have you got back your memories!
我现在要你大声说几个名出来听听
I want you to tell me a few names!
仆街，死蛤！
Damn it!
全家死，我们要杀你呀
I'll kill you!
你这么有义气，为什么呀！
You want to be a hero!
老友，这班人值得你为他们死吗？
Is it worthwhile?
他们救过我性命
They have saved my life.
我当那次我已经死了
I have put myself to death already.
怎样？
How is it?
他不会说的了，埋了他！
He won't tell, kill him!
你本事！
You have got guts!
东哥！
Tung!
不会吧，真是死了？
- what? Is he die? - Yes.
是！
我说给你们听
I tell you all!
大大是间接给你们害死的
Biggy was actually killed by you!
为了你们，我不用旨意升职啦！
I don't want promotion because of you!
警务署长个位我都无得做啦！
I'll be fired soon!
警务署长说即刻要拉了你们三个
The commissioners wants you under custody.
律政司就考虑是不是要告你们
The legal dept. wants to prosecute you.
就算不告，二十四小时之内
If no prosecution, they send you back in 24 hrs.
随时都会押你们返大陆
程Sir！
- Sir! - Stop.
不用Sir了，我无用
I am useless! I can't control the three of you.
我管不了你们三个
我们破了这么多案，难道无功劳吗？
we have finished many cases!
所以我才帮你们求情
So I ask for amnesty!
如果拉了阿虎那班人
Go to fix up wolf's team, there could be a chance.
或者有些转机的
那件事什么进展啊？
How are they now?
他们都叫我们准备
They ask us to be ready the job in 24 hours.
在二十四小时内随时动手
就是早两日说那间银行？
- The same bank you said before? - Yes!
是呀！
Do as you are told!
照做啦！
还有，你阿爸过了身了
And your dad is dead!
有封电报发去你的通讯地址
There was a telex at your place...
我不觉意看到的
Sorry!
对不起！
程Sir
Sir, was there any word from my father?
电报有无说我阿爸有遗言交待给我？
不知道，怕没有了！
I don't know! Sorry!
对不起！
他老味啊，我们替他搏命
Damn it, we work hard for him!
现在给他利用完了
Now he send us back, what does it mean?
又遣返我们上去，算什么意思？
你说！
You say it!
东哥，和这些人合作不过的
Tung, Mr. Ching is cunning!
阿虎这事都是推了他好些
we stop Ah Fu's operation!
不可以！
No!
由不得我们不做，现在唯有见步行步
we have started, we have to insist on!
我都不知我们现在为了什么！
I don't know what for!
你阿爸刚刚死了，他仍然这样逼你
He has no mercy, your dad just died!
你就要出卖老友
You betrayed your friend.
为了什么？为了破案哪？
why? why finish the cases?
香港有二万几个差人
There are 20,000 police in H.K.
为什么要我们破案？
why we have to do the investigation?
为了居留？
Just for staying here?
姓程那契弟吃定我们不放的了
Mr. Ching has got our weak point.
就算我们干足两年
Even if we worked for 2 years, he won't let us go.
他都不会放过我们
He will force us to carry on.
一定要我们干下去
等他可以升官发财
And he gets promoted!
我们的仇人就越来越多
And we have more enemies.
迟早学似大大这样的收场
we will end up like Biggy!
越想越心淡
I'm afraid!
上晚啊
I dreamt we went to Hawaii!
我发梦我们三个带了很多钱走去夏威夷
在沙滩里晒太阳
And sun bathing on the beach!
戴着些名牌太阳眼镜
一双一对这样
In pairs!
我就和黛安娜，京生和继红
Me and Diana, King San with Hung!
东哥你啊，说你都不信
You won't believe it Tung.
你和鬼妹啊！身材No.1的！
Your girl has good figure!
学军，我们什么身份都无，去得那里
Hok Kwan, we can't go anywhere without a passport.
我发梦而已！
I was dreaming!
我们当然不会这样做啦！
we have nowhere to go!
小姐，麻烦你
I am sorry, miss!
不用这么紧张，无事的
Don't worry, it's O.K.!
谢谢！
Thanks!
走吧！
Let's go!
机场移民局是吗？
Immigration?
我要举报一个中国籍的男人
I wanna report a Chinese male,
他行使一本姓名叫做李大忠的假护照
using a Li Tai Chung passport...
他会搭BC-100班机离境
He will take flight BC-100!
他五尺四寸高，短头发，大眼
He is 5'4", short hair, big eyes!
这些钱安全的吗？
The money has been exchanged?
全在这里了！
It's in the bag!
海关会不会查？
would the customs look at immigration?
放心啦，香港带钱出入境是自由的
H.K. has no financial control!
入去了！
Let's go!
干什么，你不开心啊？
what's upsetting?
不是，开心…！
No, I am happy.
这么快不拖我啦？
You don't miss me?
不用这么紧张，现在又不是偷渡
Don't worry, it's O.K.!
大摇大摆地行过去就得的了！
Let's go!
我不记得帮你买胃药
You line up first, I go to get the drug!
你替我排着队先啊！
你的护照就到期了
will be a change your passport!
先生，拿个护照给我看看
Mister. Can I have your passport?
先生，请你跟我入房，我有些事问你
Mister. Please come with me, we want to talk with you!
不要跑！
Don't go!
我现在个心在卜卜跳啊
My heart beats fast, go quick!
行快两步啦！
Don't worry, it's O.K.!
你定吧，无事的！
我们架车去到土瓜湾
He knew the end at To Kwa wan!
他就会发觉自己上当了啦！
打死你！
I'll kill you!
走啊…快走啊！
Get away! Get away quickly!
什么事啊？
Oh no!
干什么啊！
你干嘛你？
what are you doing?
他妈的，赶死啊！
You want to die!
那面有无啊？
- You take a look over there! - No!
无呀！
And you check the taxi station!
无呀？去的士站那面！
东哥！
Tung!
他拿了钱走？
He's take the money gone?
学军…开门！
Hok Kwan, open the door!
这些钱是呈堂的证物，你打算怎么办？
The money is evidence, what do you want to do?
我以为黛安娜真心爱我的
I thought Diana really loved me!
他说嫁给我，和我一齐走的
She said she would follow me!
那你又回来？
why did you come back?
他骗了我
She deceived me!
她另外有个情人，去到机场她出卖我
She has another man, she betrayed me at the airport.
和那些海关人员告密说我那个是假护照
She told the immigration that I had a forged passport!
给我走甩了
I managed to escaped!
和那些干警打起上来
And fought with the police.
抢了支枪，打伤了个臭男人
I snatched a gun and hurt the man.
这些事你都做得出来
How dare you!
长洲件案就来开审了
Cheung Chow's case is under proceeding.
这笔钱过两日要给回程警司
we have to return the money in two days.
现在钱不见了
The money is now lost.
还在机场干出这些事来
And you made a mess in the airport.
我们坐定监啦，你知不知呀？
we will end up in jail?
东哥！
- Tung! - Go away!
行开！
我知错了，我对你们不起
I know I was wrong, I am sorry!
我这种人不死都是无用的了
I don't deserve surviving!
我现在打死我自己来补偿我的过失
I die for my wrong doings!
行开！
Go away!
你开枪打死你自己，有个屁用呀！
It doesn't help even if you shoot yourself!
我带你两个出来
when we came here, we said live and die together.
说过三个人要同生共死
在这个这么困难的时候，你离开我们
You kill yourself at this critical moment.
这样证明你是一个懦夫
That proves you are a chicken!
证明你坚持自己的罪行到底
You are irresponsible...
你无义气，对不起我，对不起京生
you should be sorry to me and King San!
对不起你自己，你开枪啦，开枪啦…
If you have the guts, pull the trigger!
那个舞女知不知我们的身份，知不知啊？
Those ballroom-girl, do they know about you?
我全说给她听了！
I have told her!
学军！
Hok Kwan!
阿虎啊！
Ah Fu!
入去先啊！
Get in!
亚虎，这么夜呀！
Ah Fu, you've come here at night!
你们准备好发财未呀？
Are you ready to get rich?
现在集合，明日行动！
we gather here and do it tomorrow!
今晚要集宿和开会
we have a meeting tonight.
精神啊，走吧！
Cheer up, let's go!
是这里了，入来！
It's here, come in!
所有传呼机大家都交出来
Leave your pager here, and stay here!
不要出去
过来，坐！
Come, sit!
几百万就在对面
The few million dollars are over there.
看着架解款车来才过去
we go over after seeing the armor truck.
有什么风吹草动，随时可以看到
we can see if anything goes wrong.
又不用怕塞车，很好吧！
No traffic jam, good spot!
不用这么紧张
I'll tell you the details!
一会我会说清那些细节给你们听
轻松一下先吧！
Relax!
坐啊，来！
Come, sit!
打一、二百？
$100 or $200?
是，照旧了！
Yes!
你都来干什么？
what are you doing here?
煮饭！
To cook!
你明日第一次干，你小心些啊
Be careful tomorrow for your first time!
我叫了阿哥看着你的啦！
My brother will take care of you!
我会小心！
I'll be careful!
每一次阿哥出去干
whenever my brother commits a crime.
我都会担心到几个礼拜睡不着
I can't sleep for weeks!
今次还要担心你
I have to worry about you too.
你要应承我，阿哥和你都不会有事的
Promise me you'll be alright!
臭婊子，打死你…！
Bad smell, go to hell...
他无事呀？
Is he alright?
无事的！
O.K.!
你无事呀？
Something wrong with you?
他每次做事前都是这样的了
He's like this every time!
做好作战的心理准备
To be ready for the fight!
明日可以少个的
It's O.K. if we had one less.
不用担心，你不要看他这样
Don't worry, it will be O.K.!
他临场好勇的，他花名叫丧军呀！
He is very brutal doing his job!
我东哥说什么，我就干什么，无两句的
I do whenever my brother tells me!
叫我死，我就即刻死，不会托手挣的
If he wants me dead, I'll kill myself!
看看，他真是又狼又丧，八万！
See, he is bloody mad, Pak Man!
九章啦，你还打！
Nine blocks already, be careful!
还未联络到他们！
Can't contact him!
你的意思是说他们三个
They have joined the gang!
现在已经同那班悍匪在一起
明日就去打劫
And they will go along with the project.
是，天光之前我会去目的地那里布防
we carry out our plan before dawn!
这三个在建联走出来的卧底
The three Kin-Luen bastards!
明日和那班人一起中伏
will be trapped with the gang tomorrow.
如果打起上来
If there was exchange of fire.
在混乱之中他们好可能会有伤亡
would they be hurt too?
在一个小时之前所有负责行动的伙计
An hour ago, the special task force!
都收到他们三个的相
Have got their pictures!
不过枪战起上来，很难说的！
But it's hard to say if it is chaotic!
有一句说话，我只对你一个人说
I want to talk to you alone!
今晚在机场闯祸那家伙
About the incidence at the airport tonight.
已经证实了就是学军
It was done by Hok Kwan!
你的卧底计划根本是彻底失败
Your understand was a total failure.
在这一年来
In the past year, they had commit a lot of serious crime.
他们做了很多非常过份的事
如果这些事一旦穿了出去
In other words, if it got revealed.
我们警方就会受到所有舆论界的攻击
The police will be attacked by the media.
我和你的职位前途就即刻玩完
we don't have our future anymore.
幸好现在知道这个计划的人
Lucky only you and I know about it!
都还是很少
如果明日他们三个都被人打死了的话
If they all get killed tomorrow!
这样我们当这件事从来无发生过
Then nothing has ever happened!
你明白我的意思了吗？
Do you know what I mean?
你的！
Yours!
那两件是美国货来
They are from America!
这件是我自己用铜片做的
I made this out of copper!
虽然是重些，h些
It is a little bit heavy.
不过普通的点三八点二二
Normal pistols can't make a hole on it.
都打不穿的
来，京生，你穿！
Come, King San, look!
我一向都不信这些东西
I don't trust this!
来啊，你是新人呀！
You are freshman, you wear it!
他真是丧了！
Something wrong with him!
小姐，我们是差人
Miss, we're the police.
想借你的阳台用一下，麻烦你开门！
Can we stay on the balcony!
无人在家啊
Nobody's home!
我们是特别行动组的
we're special task force!
想借你的阳台
we wanna stay on the balcony...
监视对面间银行
to keep an eye on the bank!
我阿妈去了买菜，我拿不到主意的
My mum is out, can't let you in!
有人想打劫对面间银行
I wish that you can help, it's fatal!
麻烦你帮帮手
I am a woman, not convenient!
我一个女人，不方便的！
不用了，隔壁那间搞定了
Next door would be O.K.
无可能的！无可能的！
Impossible!
上晚机场发生袭警开枪事件
A police was attacked at the airport.
一个持假护照离境的嫌疑犯
A suspect with forged passport.
抢走警员佩枪
Snatched the police pistol and hurting a man.
并枪伤一名中国籍男子
事后该名男子在医院接受记者的访问
Our reporter has interviewed the two victims.
是他，就是他了，是他抢我的钱
It's him, he has robbed my money!
他是大陆差人，他是大陆差人来的
He is a cop from China!
是他自己说给我听的
He said he was a Chinese policeman.
那个人说自己是大陆差人
现在替警方办事
Now working as an informer.
警方怎说？
what did the police respond?
警方说根本无这回事，但是我就不信
They deny it, but I don't believe them!
他们根本无通缉他的
The police is not trying to catch him.
那些差人帮着他
He is at large and can always threaten me!
难保他又再开枪打我的
I want 24 hours protection from the police.
我要求警方二十四小时保护我
大陆差人？
Police from China?
是他们杀死了大江那几兄弟
You killed the Kwong brothers.
学军，打火机是他们手上
Hok Kwan, they have the lighter.
大大是他们杀死的
They killed Biggy!
开门…！
Open the door...what's happening inside?
什么事呀？
东哥…你怎样？
Tung, are you alright?
看着学军！
Look Hok Kwan!
你即刻带两班伙计上去
Send someone to search the top!
学军！
Hok Kwan!
阿虎…！
Ah Fu...!
你…你出卖我！
You betrayed me!
京生，京生…！
King San...!
别动！
Don't move!
巷里面的人听着
The ones in the alley, you have 3 minutes!
我们现在给三分钟你弃械投降
如不答应，我们就会使用武力
Drop your weapons or I forced out!
程Sir，他们出来了
Sir, they are coming out!
不要开枪啊…！
Don't shoot!
谁个开枪的，我就打死这个差佬先了！
I'll kill him whoever fires!
我是郭学军
I am Hok Kwan!
程Sir在不在这里？我要见程Sir！
Is Mr. Ching here? I wanna see him!
退后啊，听不听到啊？
Move back, did you hear me?
我最多和他揽着一齐死
Or we die together!
开火！
Fire!
姓程的！
Mr. Ching.
你们不要过来，叫他们退后二十码
Don't come over, move back 20 yards.
退后二十码，这是命令！
Move back 20 yards, it's an order!
你出卖我们？
You betrayed us?
你开枪就会给人打到像蜜蜂窝似的
If you fire, you get shot!
我预了啦！
I don't care!
你杀我无用的！
It's no use killing me!
杀学军不是我的意思
It's not my idea to kill Hok Kwan.
我是照命令做，我都不赞成
It was an order, I didn't agree.
我和他们辩到面红耳绿
I had argued with them, but they wouldn't listen.
他们都是不接受
Your were a soldier, you should understand.
你当过兵的
你应该明白下级服从上司的命令
是无可奈何的
The lower ranks have to obey all the time.
而且学军上晚在机场里面
And Hok Kwan made such a big mess...
弄这么大件事出来
he was surely sentenced to death.
他等于一个已经判了刑的死囚
而且牺牲了他，我才有弯转余地
To sacrifice him, I've got an alternative.
我这样做才可以帮到你
Then I can help you!
李向东，你相信我，我保证你无事
Li Heung Tung, trust me! I promise you be alright!
就算是上级的命令
That's an order, but don't have to obey!
亦未必一定要服从
如果上级要我杀一群无辜的妇孺
If I was ordered to kill a kid!
我是绝对不会接受
I won't obey!
我要问过我自己的良心先
I am conscientious!
你下令开火
You gave the order, so you are responsible!
你就要对这件事负责任
李向东，你想不想在这里居留呀？
Li Heung Tung, do you want to stay?
你不要再骗我，你说的话我不会听
Don't lie to me, I won't trust you!
我们三个人偷渡出来时候
what did we say when sneaking in...
曾经说过同生共死
生，一齐生，死，一齐死！
to live and die together!
再见
Goodbye!